<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feature
      id="de.mpc.pia.feature"
      label="PIA"
      version="1.1.0.qualifier">

    <description>
    PIA - Protein Inference Algorithms
----------------------------------

PIA is a toolbox for MS based protein inference and identification analysis.

PIA allows you to inspect the results of common proteomics spectrum
identification search engines, combine them semlessly and conduct statistical
analyses. The main focus of PIA lays on the integrated inference algorithms,
i.e. concluding the proteins from a set of identified spectra. But it also
allows you to inspect your peptide spectrum matches, calculate FDR values across
different search engine results and visualize the correspondence between PSMs,
peptides and proteins.

For more information, please go to:
https://github.com/mpc-bioinformatics/pia
 
    </description>

    <copyright>
    Copyright Ruhr-Universitaet Bochum, Medizinisches Proteom-Center, 2013-2015

    </copyright>

    <license>
    --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
                      PIA - Protein Inference Algorithms
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Copyright Ruhr-Universitaet Bochum, Medizinisches Proteom-Center, 2013-2015

This software is released under a three-clause BSD license:

Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification,
are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:

* Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this
  list of conditions and the following disclaimer.

* Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this
  list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or
  other materials provided with the distribution.

* Neither the name of any author or any participating institution may be used to
  endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific prior
  written permission.

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS &quot;AS IS&quot; AND
ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED
WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE
DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR
ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES
(INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES;
LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON
ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT
(INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS
SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.

    </license>

	<plugin
		id="de.mpc.pia"
		download-size="0"
		install-size="0"
		version="0.0.0"
		unpack="false"/>


	<plugin id="de.mpc.pia.macosx.x86_64"
		os="macosx"
		arch="x86_64"
		download-size="0"
		install-size="0"
		version="0.0.0"
		fragment="true"/>

	<plugin id="de.mpc.pia.linux.x86_64"
		os="linux"
		arch="x86_64"
		download-size="0"
		install-size="0"
		version="0.0.0"
		fragment="true"/>

	<plugin id="de.mpc.pia.linux.x86"
		os="linux"
		arch="x86"
		download-size="0"
		install-size="0"
		version="0.0.0"
		fragment="true"/>

	<plugin id="de.mpc.pia.win32.x86_64"
		os="win32"
		arch="x86_64"
		download-size="0"
		install-size="0"
		version="0.0.0"
		fragment="true"/>

	<plugin id="de.mpc.pia.win32.x86"
		os="win32"
		arch="x86"
		download-size="0"
		install-size="0"
		version="0.0.0"
		fragment="true"/>


	<plugin
		id="de.mpc.pia.knime.nodes"
		download-size="0"
		install-size="0"
		version="0.0.0"
		unpack="false"/>


</feature>
